Honey, have you seen my wallet?
亲爱的,我的皮夹呢？
Isn't it on the bedside table?
不是在床头桌上吗？
Now listen, we're running a little late.
你看,我们就快迟到了
I know.
我知道
How do I look?
我看起来怎么样？
Perfect.
美极了
Is my hair okay?
我的发型还行吗？
It's great.
挺好
You're not even looking at it.
你看都没看一眼
It's beautiful.
真的很漂亮
You always look beautiful.
你总是这么漂亮
Did you give Roz the phone and pager numbers?
你把电话和寻呼号码给罗丝了吗？
Yeah, I put it on the fridge. Let's go.
是的,贴在冰箱上了,走吧
Coming.
就来
All right.
好了
I'm ready.
我收拾好了
What's the babysitter's name?
那个保姆叫什么？
Roz.
罗丝
Okay, Roz, we're going now.
好的,罗丝,我们走了
You look amazing, Mrs.Harford.
你真是太美了,哈佛太太
Thank you. Helena, are you ready for bed?
谢谢, 海莲娜,可以睡觉了吗？
Yes, Mommy. Can I stay up and watch The Nutcracker?
是的,妈妈,我能先看完"胡桃夹子"吗？
- What time's it on? - 9:00.
-几点开始？ -9:00
- You can watch that. - Can I stay up until you get home?
-好的,你看吧 -我能等你们回家再睡吗？
- No, darling. - It'll be a little late for that.
-不行,亲爱的 -那可要到很晚才行
The phone number is on the fridge...
电话号码在冰箱上...
...and there's food in there, so help yourself.
...冰箱里有吃的,你随意好了
We shouldn't be later than 1:00.
我们应该不会超过1:00
- I'll hold our cab to take you home. - Thanks, Dr.Harford.
-我会留住计程车好送你回家 -谢谢,哈佛医生
You be good, baby.
乖乖听话,宝贝
- Good night, sweetheart. - See you in the morning.
-晚安,宝贝 -早上见
- Victor, Illona. - Bill, Alice.
-维克多,艾诺娜 -比尔,爱丽丝
- Merry Christmas. - Thank you for coming.
-圣诞快乐 -谢谢赏光
- Thanks so much for coming. - We wouldn't miss it for the world.
-真感谢你们能来 -我们怎么都不会错过这样的聚会
Alice, look at you. God, you're absolutely stunning!
爱丽丝,老天,你真让人目眩神迷
I don't say that to all the women. Do I?
我可不是对谁都这么说,是吧？
- Yes, he does. - He does?
-确实如此 -是吗？
That osteopath you sent me to, the guy that worked on my arm?
记得你为我介绍的那个骨科医生吗？
- You ought to see my serve now. - He's the top man in New York.
-你该看看我现在的发球 -他是纽约的头一号
I could have told you that, looking at his bill.
看他的帐单就知道你说的没错
Go inside, have a drink, enjoy the party.
进去喝点东西轻松一下吧
I'll see you in a little bit. Thanks for coming.
我们呆会见,谢谢赏光
Do you know anyone here?
这有你认识的人吗？
Not a soul.
一个都没有
Why do you think Ziegler invites us to these things every year?
为什么齐格勒 每年都邀请我们参加这类聚会？
This is what you get for making house calls.
这就是作为私人医生能得到的待遇
You see that guy at the piano?
看到那个钢琴师没有？
I went to medical school with him.
是我上医学院时的同学
Really?
是吗？
He plays pretty good for a doctor.
作为医生来说他弹得确实不错
He's not a doctor. He dropped out.
他不是医生,中途就辍学了
Ladies and gentlemen, I hope you're enjoying yourselves.
女士们先生们,祝你们玩得开心
The band's going to take a break. We'll be back in 10 minutes.
乐队现在休息片刻,10分钟后就回来
Thank you.
谢谢
Let's go over and say hello.
我们过去打个招呼
I desperately need to go to the bathroom.
亲爱的,我急着上洗手间
You go and say hello, and I'll meet you where? At the bar?
你自己去吧,呆会在哪见？吧台好吗？
Good.
好的
Nightingale.
南丁格尔
Nick Nightingale!
尼克-南丁格尔
Oh, my God! Bill.
哦,我的天,比尔
Bill Harford! How the hell are you, buddy?
比尔-哈佛,你怎么样,伙计？
- How long has it been? - I don't know. 10 years?
-多久不见了？ -不知道,有10年吗？
And a couple.
恐怕不止
- Do you have time for a drink? - Sure.
-有时间喝一杯吗？ -当然
You haven't changed a bit.
你一点都没变
Thanks, I think. So how you doing?
谢谢,但愿如此,你怎么样？
Not too bad, you know. Not too bad.
还行,不算太糟
I see you've become a pianist.
看来你改行做钢琴家了
Oh, yes, well, my friends call me that.
没错,朋友都这么叫我
How about you? You still in the doctor business?
你呢？还在从医吗？
You know what they say: "Once a doctor, always a doctor."
要知道有句老话说: "一日从医,终生从医"
Yes, or in my case: "Never a doctor, never a doctor."
没错,但我的情形却是: "从未从医,永不从医"
I never did understand why you walked away.
我无法理解你为什么要放弃
It's a nice feeling. I do it a lot.
因为感觉很好,我喜欢放弃
Cheers.
干杯
Excuse me. Nick, I need you a minute.
打搅,尼克,得请你过去了
Be right with you.
马上就来
I gotta go do something. If I don't catch you later...
我得去忙了,如果回头找不到你...
...I'll be down at the Village for two weeks at the Sonata Cafe.
...我这两周都会呆在 维吉区的"奏鸣曲咖啡"酒吧
- Stop by if you get a chance. - I'll be there.
-有机会的话可以来找我 -我会去的
- It's great seeing you. - Good seeing you too, man.
-见到你真高兴 -我也是,伙计
I'm absolutely certain of it.
我绝不怀疑这一点
My name is Sandor Szavost. I'm Hungarian.
我是桑多-萨乌斯,匈牙利人
My name is Alice Harford.
我是爱丽丝-哈佛
I'm American.
美国人
Delighted to meet you, Alice.
很高兴认识你,爱丽丝
Did you ever read the Latin poet Ovid on The Art of Love?
你看过拉丁诗人奥维德的"爱的艺术"吗？
Didn't he wind up all by himself...
他最终不还是形单影只...
...crying his eyes out...
...痛哭流涕...
...in some place with a very bad climate?
...呆在一个气候极其恶劣的地方吗？
But he also had a good time first.
但起初他也有过一段美好时光
A very good time.
一段非常美好的时光
Are you here with anyone tonight, Alice?
今晚是有人陪你来的吗,爱丽丝？
With my husband.
是和我丈夫一起来的
Oh, how sad.
太遗憾了
But then I'm sure he's the sort of man who wouldn't mind if we danced.
但我确信他不是那种 会因为我们跳舞而介意的人
What do you do, Alice?
你是干哪一行的,爱丽丝？
Well, at the moment...
这个嘛...眼下...
...I'm looking for a job.
...我正要找份工作
I used to manage an art gallery in SoHo.
我曾在休南区经营一家艺术画廊
But it went broke.
但已经关闭了
What a shame.
真可惜
I have some friends in the art game.
我在艺术界有些朋友
Perhaps I can be of some help.
也许我能帮点忙
Thank you.
谢谢
Someone you know?
是熟人吗？
My...
是我...
...husband.
...丈夫
Don't you think one of the charms of marriage...
你不觉得婚姻的魅力之一...
...is that it makes deception a necessity for both parties?
...就是有必要为了对方而编造谎言吗？
May I ask why a beautiful woman...
恕我冒昧,为什么一个能得到...
...who could have any man in this room, wants to be married?
...这屋子里任何男人的 美丽女人会想结婚呢？
Why wouldn't she?
她为什么不呢？
Is it as bad as that?
有那么糟吗？
As good as that.
是有那么好才对
Do you know Nuala Windsor?
你认识卢娜-温莎吗？
No, and it's very lovely to meet you both.
不,但很高兴认识你们
How do you spell Nuala?
卢娜该怎么拼？
N-U-A-L-A.
N-U-A-L-A
You don't remember me, do you?
你不记得我了,对吧？
You were very kind to me once.
有一次你对我很温柔
Only once? That sounds like a terrible oversight!
只有一次？听起来象是一个美妙的夜晚
I was doing a photo session in Rockefeller Plaza...
当时我正在洛克菲勒广场拍一组照片...
...on a very windy day...?
...那天风非常大...？
- And you got something in your eye. - Just about half of Fifth Avenue.
-有东西吹进了你眼睛里 -不过是半条第五大街而已
You were such a gentleman! You gave me your handkerchief...
你当时真有绅士风度, 把你的手帕递给了我...
...which was also clean.
...很干净的手帕
That is the kind of hero I can be sometimes.
我偶尔也能来一回英雄救美
You know why women used to get married, don't you?
你知道女人为什么习惯于结婚吗？
Why don't you tell me?
为什么不说说看？
It was the only way they could lose their virginity...
那是她们能失去童贞,然后...
...and be free to do what they wanted with other men.
...和其他男人尽情作乐的唯一方法
The ones they really wanted.
和她们真正想要的男人
Fascinating.
太有趣了
Do you know what's so nice about doctors?
你知道做医生的好处是什么吗？
Usually a lot less than people imagine.
通常远不如人们想象的那样好
They always seem so...
他们似乎总是那么...
...knowledgeable.
...见多识广
Oh, they are very knowledgeable...
他们确实见识很广...
...about all sorts of things.
...不管在哪方面
But I bet they work too hard.
但我打赌他们工作一定很辛苦
Just think of all they miss.
想想他们错过的一切就能知道
You're probably right.
也许你是对的
Ladies, where exactly are we going?
女士们,我们到底要去哪？
Exactly?
到底去哪？
Where the rainbow ends.
彩虹的尽头
Where the rainbow ends?
彩虹的尽头？
Don't you want to go where the rainbow ends?
你不想去彩虹的尽头吗？
Well, let's find out.
我们不妨找找看
Excuse me, ladies. Sorry, Dr.Harford.
打扰一下,女士们, 对不起,哈佛医生
Could you come with me for a moment? Something for Mr.Ziegler.
请跟我来一下好吗？齐格勒先生有事找您
Fine.
好的
To be continued?
稍后再聊好吗？
Bill, thanks for coming.
比尔,你能来太好了
We had a little accident here.
我们这有点小小的意外
What happened?
怎么回事？
Well, she was...
她...
She was shooting up and she had a bad reaction.
她打了一针但是反应不太妙
What did she take?
注射的是什么？
A speedball or a snowball or whatever the hell they call it.
"快球"或是"雪球", 天知道他们管这叫什么
It's heroin and coke.
是海洛因加古柯碱
Heroin and coke?
海洛因加古柯碱？
Anything else?
还有别的吗？
We had a couple of drinks, some champagne. That was it.
我们喝了几杯,是香槟,就这些
How long has she been like this?
她这样子多久了？
What's her name?
她叫什么？
Mandy.
曼蒂
Can you hear me, Mandy?
听到我说话吗？曼蒂？
Can you hear me? Move your head if you can hear me.
能听到吗？能听到的话就摇摇头
Move your head if you can hear me, Mandy. There you go.
如果能听到就摇摇头,曼蒂,很好
You can hear me.
你能听到
Can you open your eyes for me? Mandy, can you do that?
能睁开眼睛吗？曼蒂,能行吗？
Let me see you open your eyes. There you go, come on.
睁开眼睛,你行的,来吧
Come on, look at me. Look at me.
来吧,看着我,看着我
Look at me. Look at me.
看着我,看着我
Look at me. Look at me, Mandy.
看着我,看着我,曼蒂
Good.
很好
I love Victor's art collection, don't you?
我喜欢维克多的艺术收藏,你呢？
It's wonderful.
是的,非常漂亮
Have you ever seen his sculpture gallery?
你看过他的雕塑艺廊吗？
I haven't.
没有
He has a wonderful collection of Renaissance bronzes.
他有一批很精美的 文艺复兴时期的青铜藏品
Do you like the period?
你喜欢那个时期吗？
I do.
是的
I adore it.
我非常喜欢
The sculpture gallery is upstairs.
雕塑艺廊就在楼上
Would you like to see it?
你想去看看吗？
I can show it to you.
我可以做你的导游
We won't be gone long.
用不了多长时间
Maybe...
也许...
...not just...
...还是...
...now.
...下次吧
That was really one hell of a scare you gave us, kiddo.
你真把我们给吓死了,大姐
Sorry.
对不起
How are you feeling now, Mandy?
你现在感觉怎样？曼蒂
Better.
好多了
You are a very, very lucky girl.
你是个非常非常幸运的女孩
You know that?
懂我意思吧？
I know.
是的
You're gonna be okay this time.
这次你会平安无事
But you can't keep doing this.
但你不能继续那样做
You understand?
懂吗？
You're going to need some rehab. You know that, don't you?
你应该去康复中心, 你知道那是什么地方,对吧？
I know.
知道
Well, Victor...
维克多...
...I'll leave the rest to you.
...剩下的就交给你了
Is it okay if I dress her and get her out of here?
现在让她穿上衣服离开不会有事吧？
No, I'd keep her here for another hour.
不行,得让她再休息一个小时
Another hour?
一个小时？
Then I'd have someone take her home.
然后再找人送她回家
Good night, Mandy.
晚安,曼蒂
I can't thank you enough for this.
真不知该怎么谢你
- You saved my ass. - I'm glad I was here.
-你救了我的命 -不用客气
Bill, I probably...
比尔,也许我...
I know I don't have to mention this...
我知道用不着我多说...
...but this is just between us.
...但这事就你知我知,好吗？
Of course.
当然
Thanks.
谢谢
I think I've had a little too much champagne.
我想...我香槟喝多了点
I think I have to go and find my husband now.
我现在得去找我丈夫了
But I'm sure he'll be all right on his own a little longer.
但我确信他单独呆一会不会有问题
Yes...
是啊...
...but will I?
...但我呢？
Of course you will.
你当然也不会
I really have to go. I have to go.
我真的该走了,我得走了
You don't, you know.
你明白自己并不想走
Yes, I do.
不,我要走
I must see you again.
我一定要再见到你
- That's impossible. - Why?
-不可能 -为什么？
Because...
因为...
...I'm married.
...我结婚了
Good morning, Lisa.
早,莉莎
Good morning, doctor. Your mail.
早,医生,你的信
Good. Please ask Janelle to bring me my coffee.
请让詹妮尔给我送咖啡来
- Sure. - Thank you.
-好的 -谢谢
- Good morning, Sarah. - Good morning, doctor.
-早,莎拉 -早,医生
Okay. That's fine. You can put your gown on.
很正常,把手术服穿上吧
Hold this for Mommy.
帮妈妈拿一下
Looking forward to Christmas?
盼望过圣诞节吗？
Does this hurt?
疼不疼？
Right there?
是这吗？
Daddy's gonna like that.
爸爸一定会喜欢
Very good choice.
你真有眼光
"...before me...
"...在我之前...
...when I jump into my bed."
...当我要跳到我的床上时"
We should call the Zieglers and thank them for the party.
我们该打电话给齐格勒 为那个晚会向他道谢
I've taken care of that.
我已经打过了
Good.
那就好
So how do you feel about wrapping the rest of the presents?
那你想把剩下的礼物都包好吗？
Let's do that tomorrow.
明天再说吧
Tell me something.
告诉我一件事
Those two girls...
昨晚宴会上...
...at the party last night...
...那两个女孩...
Did you...
你...
...by any chance...
...有没有...
...happen to...
...机会...
...fuck them?
...和她们上床？
What?
什么？
What are you talking about?
你都在说什么？
I'm talking about the two girls...
我是说,很明显...
...that you were so blatantly hitting on.
...你对那两个女孩很着迷
I wasn't hitting on anybody.
我可没对任何人着迷
Who were they?
她们是什么人？
They were just a couple of models.
几个模特罢了
And where did you disappear to with them for so long?
那你和她们消失那么久是去哪了？
Wait a minute.
等等...
I didn't disappear with anybody.
我没和任何人一起消失
Ziegler wasn't feeling too well...
齐格勒感觉不太舒服...
...and I got called upstairs to see him.
...让人叫我去楼上给他看看
Anyway, who was the guy you were dancing with?
话说回来,和你跳舞的那个家伙是谁？
A friend of the Zieglers.
是齐格勒的一个朋友
What did he want?
他想干嘛？
Sex...
马上...
...upstairs.
...去楼上
Then and there.
做爱
Is that all?
就这些？
Yeah, that was all.
对,就这些
Just wanted to fuck my wife.
想和我太太睡觉
That's right.
没错
Well, I guess that's understandable.
我想这可以理解
Understandable?
可以理解？
Because you are a very...
因为你是个非常...
...very beautiful woman.
...非常漂亮的女人
Wait.
等等
Because I'm a beautiful woman...
因为我是个漂亮女人...
...the only reason any man ever wants to talk to me...
...所以凡是男人 想找我聊天的唯一理由...
...is because he wants to fuck me. Is that what you're saying?
...就是想和我上床, 你是这个意思吗？
Well, I don't think it's quite that black and white...
我不认为绝对是那样...
...but I think we both know what men are like.
...但我们都清楚男人喜欢什么
So on that basis...
照这么说...
...I should conclude that you wanted to fuck those two models.
...我可以认定你想和那两个模特上床了
There are exceptions.
总会有例外
And what makes you an exception?
你凭什么说自己是个例外？
What makes me an exception is that...
我之所以认为自己是个例外...
...I happen to be in love with you.
...是因为我爱的是你
And because we're married...
因为我们已经结婚...
...and because I would never lie to you...
...因为我决不会欺骗你...
...or hurt you.
...或者伤害你
Do you realize that what you're saying...
你有没有意识到你的意思是...
...is that the only reason you wouldn't fuck those models...
...你不会 和那两个模特上床的唯一理由...
...is out of consideration for me?
...是出于尊重我？
Not because you really wouldn't want to.
而不是因为你确实不想
Let's just relax, Alice.
冷静一下,爱丽丝
This pot is making you aggressive.
大麻让你有点失控了
No! It's not the pot. It's you!
不,这不关大麻的事,是因为你
Why can't you ever give me a straight fucking answer?
为什么你就不能坦白回答我？
I was under the impression that's what I was doing.
我觉得我就是在实话实说
I don't even know what we're arguing about here.
我都不知道我们现在在争什么
I'm not arguing.
我没争
I'm just trying to find out where you're coming from.
我只想找出你的出发点
Where I'm coming from?
我的出发点？
Let's say, for example, you have some gorgeous woman...
这么说吧,假如有个很漂亮的女人...
...standing in your office naked...
...一丝不挂站在你的办公室里...
...and you're feeling her fucking tits.
...而你在检查她那该死的乳房
Now, what I want to know...
我想知道...
I want to know what you're thinking about when you're squeezing them.
我想知道 当你捏它们的时候你在想些什么？
Alice, I happen to be a doctor.
艾莉丝,我可是个医生
It's all very impersonal...
绝对不会心存杂念
...and you know there's always a nurse present.
...而且你也知道总会有护士在场
So when you're feeling tits, it's nothing more than your professionalism?
所以你捏弄乳房的时候, 纯粹只是工作需要,对吗？
Exactly.
一点不错
Sex is the last thing on my mind when I'm with a patient.
我面对病人时绝对不会想入非非
Now, when she is having her little titties squeezed...
那么,当她的小奶头被捏弄时...
...do you think she ever has fantasies...
...你觉得她会不会幻想...
...about what handsome Dr.Bill's dickie might be like?
...帅气的比尔医生的老二是什么样子？
Come on, I can assure you sex is the last thing...
够了,我敢担保这个假定的...
...on this fucking hypothetical woman patient's mind.
...见鬼的女病人决不会胡思乱想
And what makes you so sure?
你凭什么如此肯定？
If for no better reason...
最大的理由就是...
...because she's afraid of what I might find.
...因为她会担心我的检查结果
So after you tell her that everything's fine, what then?
那在你告诉她一切正常之后呢？ 然后会怎样？
What then?
然后怎样？
I don't know, Alice...
怎么说呢,爱丽丝...
Women don't...
女人不会...
They basically just don't think like that.
她们通常不会那样想
Millions of years of evolution, right?
数百万年的进化结果,对不对？
Men have to stick it every place they can...
男人有机会就到处鬼混...
...but for women, it is just about security and commitment...
...但对女人而言 就只是安全感和责任感...
...and whatever the fuck else!
...以及其他的鬼话
A little oversimplified, Alice. But yes, something like that.
你说得太绝对了, 但有些事情确实是这样
If you men only knew.
是不是只有你们男人才知道
What I do know is you got stoned, you tried to pick a fight...
我只知道你已经神智不清, 你在找我的碴...
...and now you're trying to make me jealous.
...现在又想让我嫉妒
But you're not the jealous type, are you?
可你不是那种会嫉妒的人,对吗？
No, I'm not.
对,我不是
You've never been jealous about me, have you?
你从没为我吃过醋是不是？
No, I haven't.
是的,没有
And why haven't you ever been jealous about me?
为什么你不会为我吃醋？
Well, I don't know, Alice. Maybe because you're my wife.
我不知道,爱丽丝, 也许是因为你是我妻子
Maybe because you're the mother of my child...
也许是因为你是我孩子的母亲...
...and I know you would never be unfaithful to me.
...而且我知道你决不会对我不忠
You are very, very sure of yourself...
你非常非常相信自己...
...aren't you?
...是不是？
No.
不
I'm sure of you.
我是相信你
Do you think that's funny?
你觉得这很可笑？
All right. Fuck it.
去他妈的
Now we get the fucking laughing fit, right?
这种状况他妈的很可笑,是不是？
Do you...
你...
Do you remember last summer at Cape Cod?
你记得去年夏天在科特角的事吗？
Do you remember one night in the dining room...
记不记得有天晚上在餐厅...
...there was this young naval officer...
...有个年轻海军军官...
...and he was sitting near our table with two other officers?
...和另外两个军官坐在我们旁边的桌上？
No.
不
The waiter brought him a message, at which point he left.
侍者给他带了个口信,然后他就走了
Nothing rings a bell?
一点印象都没有吗？
...I first saw him that morning in the lobby.
...我第一次见到他是那天早上在大堂
He was checking into the hotel...
他当时在登记住宿...
...and he was following the bellboy with his luggage...
...然后门房拿上行李领着他...
...to the elevator.
...去坐电梯
He glanced at me as he walked past. Just a glance.
经过我身边时他瞥了我一眼,就一眼
Nothing more.
仅此而已
But I could hardly...
却让我几乎无法...
...move.
...动弹
That afternoon...
那天下午...
...Helena went to the movies with her friend...
...海莲娜和她的朋友去看电影
...and you and I made love.
...我们俩做爱
And we made plans about our future...
然后一起计划我们的未来...
...and we talked about Helena.
...还谈到了海莲娜
And yet...
可是...
...at no time...
...不管什么时候...
...was he ever...
...他...
...out of my mind.
...都在我脑子里盘旋
And I thought if he wanted me...
我那时在想,如果他想要我...
...even if it was only...
...哪怕只是...
...for one night...
...一个晚上...
...I was ready to give up everything.
...我都愿意放弃一切
You.
你
Helena.
海莲娜
My whole fucking future.
整个见鬼的将来
Everything.
所有一切
And yet it was weird, because at the same time...
但是很奇怪,因为我在这么想的同时...
...you were dearer to me than ever.
...却比以往任何时候都更爱你
And at that moment, my love for you...
那时我对你的爱...
...was both...
...夹杂着...
...tender and sad.
...痛苦和哀伤
I barely slept that night...
那晚我几乎无法入睡...
...and I woke up the next morning in a panic.
...而且第二天早上是在恐慌之中醒过来
I didn't know whether I was afraid that he had left...
我不知道自己是担心他已经离去...
...or that he might still be there.
...还是害怕他可能仍然在那
But by dinner...
但是吃晚饭时...
...I realized he was gone...
...我知道他已经走了...
...and I was...
...而我也...
...relieved.
...放心了
Yes, this is Dr.Harford.
是的,我是哈佛医生
When did it happen?
什么时候的事？
I have the address.
我有地址
Thank you.
谢谢
Lou Nathanson just died.
卢-内森逊死了
I think I have to go over there and show my face.
我想我得过去露个面
- Hello, Rosa. - Good evening, Dr.Harford.
-你好,罗莎 -晚上好,哈佛医生
- How is Miss Nathanson? - Not so good. She's in the bedroom.
-内森逊小姐怎么样？ -不太好,她在卧室
Thank you.
谢谢
Come in.
请进
Marion...
玛莉恩...
Oh, Dr.Harford...
哈佛医生...
How good of you to come.
你能来太好了
I came as soon as I got the message.
我一得到消息就赶来了
Thank you.
谢谢
- I'm so sorry. - Thank you.
-我很遗憾 -谢谢
Your father was...
你父亲...
He was a very brave man.
他是个非常勇敢的人
Oh, thank you.
谢谢
How are you holding up?
你还撑得住吧？
I'm a bit numb.
我有点麻木
I don't think it's really sunk in yet.
我不敢相信这是真的
Would you like to sit down?
还是坐下再说吧
It's so unreal.
太难以接受了
Daddy had such a good day.
他白天还好好的
His mind was clear, and he remembered so many things.
头脑很清醒,还记得很多事情
Then he had a little dinner...
他还吃了点晚餐...
...and he said he felt like taking a nap.
...然后说他想休息一下
I went into the kitchen and talked to Rosa for half an hour at most...
我到厨房和罗莎聊了最多半个小时...
...and when I went to see how he was...
...当我去看他怎么样的时候...
...I just thought he was asleep.
...我还以为他是睡着了
Then I realized he wasn't breathing.
然后才发现他已经停止了呼吸
From what you've said...
照这么说...
...I'm sure your father died peacefully in his sleep.
...我相信你父亲是在睡梦中平静离去的
Oh, God, I hope so.
天啊,但愿是这样
I think I've been more afraid of the way it was going to happen...
我想我更担心的是他会走得太痛苦...
...than his death itself.
...而不是会不会离去
Have you had a chance to phone any of your relatives?
你有没有打电话通知亲友？
I tried to call my stepmother in London, but she was out.
我给伦敦的继母打过电话,但她不在
My boyfriend, Carl, is making some calls...
我男朋友卡尔正在通知亲友...
...and he'll be coming over soon.
...他很快就会过来
I think you've met Carl here a few times.
我想你在这见过他几次
Yes, I remember him. He's a teacher, isn't he?
是的,我记得,他是个老师对吧？
A math professor.
是个数学教授
We're going to get married in May.
我们打算在5月结婚
Well, that's wonderful news. Congratulations.
真是个好消息,恭喜你
Thank you.
谢谢
Carl has a new teaching appointment at the University of Michigan.
卡尔在密歇根大学有个新的教师职位
We'll be moving out there soon.
我们很快就会搬过去
Michigan's a beautiful state. I think you'll like it a lot.
密歇根是个好地方,你一定会很喜欢
It really could be a wonderful change for you, Marion.
换个环境可能对你有好处
Oh, my God, no...
天啊,不...
I love you.
我爱你
I love you, I love you, I love you.
我爱你,我爱你,我爱你...
I don't want to go away with Carl.
我不想和卡尔一起走
Marion, I don't think you realize...
玛莉恩,我想你还不明白...
I do.
我明白
Even if I'm never to see you again, I want at least to live near you.
就算我永远再见不到你, 至少也要住在离你不远的地方
Marion, listen to me. Listen to me.
玛莉恩,听我说,听我说
You're very upset, and I don't think you realize what you're saying.
你现在心情很乱, 不知道自己在说些什么
I love you.
我爱你
We barely know each other.
我们几乎不了解对方
We haven't had a single conversation about anything except your father.
除了你父亲的事我们从没聊过别的
I love you.
我爱你
That's probably Carl.
也许是卡尔
Please don't despise me.
请不要看不起我
- Hello, Rosa. - Hello, Mr.Thomas.
-你好,罗莎 -你好,托马斯先生
- Is she in the bedroom? - Yes, she is.
-她在卧室吗？ -是的
Thank you.
谢谢
Come in.
请进
Darling.
亲爱的
I'm so very sorry.
我很难过
Are you all right?
你还好吧？
I'm okay.
还好
- Dr.Harford, good evening. - Good evening, Carl.
-哈佛医生,晚上好 -晚上好,卡尔
Thank you very much for coming over here tonight.
你今晚能来真是太感谢你了
- It's the least I could do. - It means a lot to us.
-这是我起码能做到的 -但对我们意味着很多
Thank you.
谢谢
I was actually on my way out.
我得走了
Marion...
玛莉恩...
...your father was very proud of you...
...你父亲一直为你而自豪...
...and I know you gave him great comfort these last months.
...我知道 在最后几个月是你给了他很大的安慰
Thank you.
谢谢
I'll show you out.
我送你出去
Good night.
晚安
Listen to this. She had a red rose in her mouth.
...她嘴里叼着支红玫瑰
She was doing a Mexican lap dance right in my face.
在我面前跳起了艳舞
I'm serious! I got scars on the back of my neck.
真的,我脖子后边还留着疤呢
What team's this switch hitter playing for?
这娘娘腔是哪个队的？
- Looks like the pink team. - Look at this faggot!
-看来是"粉红"队 -看这个同性恋
Hey, watch it, you faggot!
看着点,同性恋
Merry Christmas, Mary!
圣诞快乐,"玛丽"
- Your butt-brothers are back there! - Prime cut of meat!
-你的老相好在这 -绝对一流
You want to take a ride in this fudge-tunnel, you stupid faggot?
想不想骑一下,死娘娘腔？
You should have tits, you're standing so close!
你应该有对大奶子,滚远点
- I got dumps that are bigger than you! - Come on, macho man!
-我拉的屎都比你那玩意要粗 -来吧,男子汉
- You want a piece of this, baby? - Exit only, honey.
-想来一下吗,宝贝？ -只许出不许进,亲爱的
Excuse me. Do you know what time it is?
打扰一下,请问几点了？
Ten past 12.
10:12
Going anywhere special?
正要去什么地方吗？
No, I'm just taking a walk.
不,只是随便走走
How'd you like to have a little fun?
想不想找点乐子？
I'm sorry?
什么？
Have a little fun?
找点乐子
I just live right down there.
我就住在这
Would you like to come inside with me?
想不想和我一起进去？
Come inside with you?
和你一起进去？
It's a lot nicer in there than it is out here.
总比在外边要好
You live in there?
你住在这？
By yourself?
一个人？
No. I have a roommate, but she's not home.
不,有个室友,但她不在
Hey, it's okay.
不会有事的
Listen, no one will bother us.
没人会打扰我们
It's okay. Come on.
不会有事,来吧
Come on.
来吧
This is it.
就是这
That's a nice tree.
好漂亮的树
Sorry about the mess. Maid's day off.
很抱歉这么乱,女佣放假了
It's...
这里...
...cozy. It's a...
...挺舒服,是个...
...cozy place.
...不错的住处
It's okay.
还行吧
Do you suppose we should talk about money?
你觉得我们该谈谈钱的事吗？
Yeah, I guess so.
我想是的
That depends on what you want to do.
这得看你想怎么做
What do you want to do?
你想怎么做？
What do you recommend?
你的意思呢？
What do I recommend?
我的意思？
I'd rather not put it into words.
我宁可来点实际的
How about you just leave it up to me?
就由我作主怎么样？
I'm in your hands.
悉听尊便
And how does 150 sound?
150怎么样？
Sounds wonderful.
很不错
Don't worry. I don't keep track of the time.
别担心,我不会限定时间
Shall we?
可以开始吗？
Excuse me.
不好意思
Is everything all right?
一切都还好吧？
I was just wondering if you were going to be much longer?
是的,我只是想知道你还要呆多久
Listen, it's a little difficult to talk right now.
听我说,现在还不能确定
It could be awhile.
也许得要一阵子
Any idea how long?
大概要多久？
No, I don't really know.
我确实说不好
We're still waiting for some relatives to arrive.
我们还在等一些亲友
Well, I'm gonna go to bed now.
是吗,那我现在去睡觉了
Was that Mrs.Dr.Bill?
那是比尔医生的太太吧？
Do you have to go?
你是不是得走了？
Do I have to go?
我是不是得走了？
I think I do.
我想是的
Are you sure?
你确定？
Yes, I'm afraid so.
恐怕是的
But listen, I want to pay you anyway.
但不管怎样我都会付钱给你
How much did you say it was? Hundred and fifty?
你刚才说的是多少？150吗？
But you know what? You don't have to bother about that.
但知道吗？你不用为这个操心
No, it's all right.
不,没关系
- No, really. You don't have to. - No, I want to.
-不,真的,你不用这样做 -不,我愿意
Really?
真的？
Well, thank you very much.
那就多谢了
Thank you.
谢谢
Would you like a table, or would you like to sit at the bar?
您愿意找张桌子还是就坐在吧台？
- I'd like a table. - Please follow me.
-我想找张桌子 -请跟我来
- Can I take your coat? - Thank you.
-我来帮您拿外套 -谢谢
Could I get you anything to drink?
您想喝点什么？
- I'd like a beer. - Certainly.
-来杯啤酒好了 -好的
One, two, one-two-three-four.
一,二,一-二-三-四
That's it for tonight, ladies and gentlemen.
今晚演出到此为止,女士们先生们
On the bass, Mr.Larry McVey. On the drums, Kip Fleming.
贝斯手,拉里-麦克维先生, 鼓手,基普-弗莱明先生
And on the guitar, the one, the only, Mr.Bobby Berman.
吉他手,独一无二的博比-伯曼先生
We'll be here for the next two weeks, so please do stop by.
接下来的两星期我们都会在这, 请多多捧场
I'm Nick Nightingale. Good night.
我是尼克-南丁格尔,晚安
- Nick, that was great. - Thanks.
-尼克,太棒了 -谢谢
- Nightingale. - Hey, Bill, you made it.
-南丁格尔 -嘿,比尔,你来了
I'm sorry, I got here just as you were finishing your last set.
真是遗憾,我到这时正赶上你谢幕
That's all right. The band sucked tonight anyway.
没关系,乐队今晚表现很差
- What are you drinking? - A vodka and tonic, please.
-你喝什么？ -伏特加加奎宁水,谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢
So what brings you out at this hour?
是什么风把你吹来的？
- I have a patient in the neighborhood. - You live in the Village?
-我有个病人住在附近 -你住在维吉区？
No, we have an apartment on Central Park West.
不,我们住在中央公园西区
You're married?
你结婚了？
Nine years.
9年了
- Any kids? - Yes, we have a 7-year-old daughter.
-有孩子吗？ -是的,有个7岁大的女儿
How about you?
你呢？
I've got a wife and four boys in Seattle.
我和妻子以及四个儿子住在西雅图
You're a long way from home.
你离家挺远啊
Well, you gotta go where the work is.
哪有工作就得去哪
Thank you.
谢谢
- Is this your band? - No, it's a pick-up band.
-这是你的乐队？ -不,是临时找来的
- Who do you normally play with? - Anybody, anywhere.
-通常都和谁合作？ -没有固定的搭档和地方
I got another gig later tonight.
今晚呆会还另有演出
You're playing somewhere else tonight?
今晚还另有演出？
They only get started around 2.
要到大概2:00开场
In the Village?
在维吉区吗？
Believe it or not, I don't actually know the address yet.
信不信由你,我还不知道确切的地址
You don't?
是吗？
No. It may sound ridiculous, but it's in a different place every time...
也许听起来很荒谬, 但每次都是在不同的地方
...and I only get it an hour or so before.
...我一小时前才能知道
- A different place every time? - So far.
-每次地方都不同？ -一直如此
What's the big mystery?
干嘛如此神秘？
Hey, man, I just play the piano.
嘿,老兄,我可是只管弹钢琴
Nick, I'm sorry. Is there something I'm missing here?
尼克,冒昧问一句, 我是不是漏掉了什么？
I play blindfolded.
我是蒙着眼睛弹
What?
什么？
You're putting me on.
你是在耍我
No, it's the truth.
不,是真的
And the last time, the blindfold wasn't on so well.
但是上次,蒙得不是很严实
Oh, man.
老天
Bill, I have seen one or two things in my life...
比尔,我这辈子也见过一点世面...
...but never...
...但从没...
...never anything like this...
...从没见过那种场面...
...and never such women.
...以及那么多的美女
Excuse me.
对不起
Yes, sir. Yes, sir, this is Nick.
是的,先生, 是的,先生,我是尼克
I know where that is.
我知道那个地方
Right.
好的
Well, I'm on my way right now.
我马上动身
Okay, sir. Thank you.
好的,先生,谢谢
What is this?
这是什么？
It's the name of a Beethoven opera, isn't it?
贝多芬一出歌剧的名字不是吗？
It's the password.
是暗号
The password?
暗号？
Yeah. Look, I'm really sorry to do this to you, Bill.
是的,我很抱歉得撇下你,比尔
I gotta get going. I gotta go.
但我得走了,得走了
You know there is no way on earth...
你该知道这是不可能的...
...that you are going to leave here without taking me with you.
...你不带上我就休想离开
- Come on, buddy, give me a break. - Nick, I'll tell you what.
-拜托,伙计,你饶了我吧 -尼克,这样吧
I've already got the password.
我已经知道暗号了
Just give me the address. I'll go there by myself...
你只要把地址给我,我自己去...
...and there won't be any connection between us whatsoever.
...这样无论如何都不会连累你
Listen, let's just say for one second...
这样吧,实话跟你说...
...that I was prepared to do that.
...就算我告诉你
You couldn't get in anyway in those clothes.
但你穿成这样还是哪也去不了
Why not?
为什么？
Because everyone is always costumed and masked.
因为每个人都穿着礼服戴着面具
Where the hell are you gonna get a costume at this hour?
这个时候你上什么鬼地方去弄礼服？
Thanks. Keep the change.
谢谢,不用找了
Yes? Who is it?
喂？是哪位？
Peter, this is Bill Harford.
彼特,我是比尔-哈佛
I apologize for disturbing you at this hour, but I need your help.
很抱歉这时候来打扰你, 但我需要你帮忙
Who is it that you want?
你想找谁？
I'm very sorry. I'm looking for Peter Grenning...
真对不起,我想找彼特-格朗宁
...the owner of Rainbow Fashions.
..."彩虹时尚"的店主
What's your name?
你是谁？
My name is Bill Harford.
我是比尔-哈佛
I'm Mr.Grenning's doctor.
格朗宁先生的医生
You are Grenning's doctor?
你是他的医生？
Okay.
好吧
Just a moment.
等一下
You are looking for Peter Grenning?
你找彼特-格朗宁？
Yes, I am.
是的
He moved to Chicago over a year ago.
他一年多前就搬到芝加哥去了
He moved to Chicago?
他搬到芝加哥去了？
I wasn't aware of that.
我一点都不知道
Then are you the present owner of Rainbow Fashions?
那"彩虹时尚"的店主现在是你了？
Yes, I am.
是的,没错
Well, first of all...
那首先...
...please let me apologize again for disturbing you at this hour, Mr...
...得请你原谅我这个时候来打扰你了, 请问怎么称呼...
Milich.
米利奇
Mr.Milich. Just to let you know that I really am Dr.Harford...
米利奇先生, 先向你证明一下我确实是哈佛医生...
...this is my New York State Medical Board card.
...这是我在纽约州的行医执照
Okay, so you are Dr.Harford.
没错,看来你确实是哈佛医生
If I see Peter, I tell him you were looking for him.
如果见到彼特,我会告诉他你在找他
Oh, no, wait. Please, please...
不,等等,拜托,拜托...
Listen, the reason that I came here tonight was...
听我说,我今晚来这的目的...
Basically, the reason is that I need a costume.
主要的目的,是想租一套衣服
And I'd be happy to pay you $ 100 over the rental price...
而且我愿意多付你100美元的租金...
...for the inconvenience.
...略作补偿
A hundred dollars?
100美元？
I don't think so.
恐怕不够
How about $200?
200美元怎么样？
Two hundred dollars over the rental price?
多付200美元租金？
Come in.
请进
Can't be too careful these days.
这年头小心点总不会错
Please.
请吧
Is it any special costume you are looking for?
你是想找什么特别的服装吗？
I need a tux, a cloak with a hood and a mask.
我需要一件小礼服, 一件带风帽的斗篷和一个面具
A cloak with a hood and a mask?
带风帽的斗篷和面具？
I think we'll find something for you.
我想应该能找到
Follow me, please.
请跟我来
Good.
太好了
Looks like alive, huh?
栩栩如生,是吧？
- It's wonderful. - Come.
-太逼真了 -来吧
So what color cloak?
斗篷要什么颜色？
Red, brown, red?
红色,棕红色？
Black.
黑色
The good doctor wouldn't like something more colorful?
这位好医生就不想打扮得更有趣点吗？
- I don't think so. - Clowns, officers, pirates?
-不用了 -小丑,警察,海盗？
No, just the tux, the black cloak...
不,只要小礼服,黑色斗篷...
With a hood and a mask.
要有风帽外加面具
May I take your coat?
脱掉外套吧
- You are medicine doctor, yes? - Yes, I am.
-你是医生,对吧？ -是的,没错
- I have some problem with my hair. - Your hair?
-我的头发有点问题 -你的头发？
It's starting to fall down too fast.
它们掉得太快了
I lost, in two weeks, a lot of hair. Mostly here.
两个星期就掉了很多,主要是这
Look at this. Here.
看,就是这
You see?
看到了？
And?
那么？
I'm afraid this really isn't my field.
这恐怕不是我的专长
What? You can't help me?
什么？你帮不了我？
No. You should see a trichologist. It's a hair specialist.
对,你该找个专治头发的专科医生
Mr.Milich, I've obviously left things a bit late tonight.
米利奇先生,我今晚确实要赶时间
So if you don't mind...
不介意的话...
I'm in hurry too, to get back to bed.
我也得抓紧时间回去睡觉
I understand.
我明白
So black cloak?
黑色斗篷是吧？
Did you hear something?
你听到没有？
What is this?
是什么声音？
What is it?
会是什么？
What on earth is going on here?!
这到底是怎么回事？
Milich, I can explain everything.
米利奇,请听我解释
You! What are you doing here?
你,你在这干什么？
I promise I'll kill you!
我发誓我要杀了你
And you! Have you no sense of decency?
还有你,你还有没有廉耻？
Gentlemen, have you no sense of decency?!
先生们,你们还有没有廉耻？
Milich, are you crazy? We were invited here by the young lady.
米利奇,你疯了吗？ 是这位小姐邀请我们来这的
Young lady? This is my daughter! Couldn't you see she's a child?
小姐？这是我女儿, 你们没看到她还是个孩子吗？
- You will have to explain to police! - To the police?!
-你得去向警察解释 -警察？
You little whore! I kill you for this.
你这小娼妇,我要杀了你
I promise, I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
我发誓,我要杀了你,我要杀了你
Hold on to that girl for me, please!
请帮我抓住那女孩
Milich, this is preposterous. The young lady invited us here.
米利奇,真是岂有此理, 是这位小姐邀请我们来的
Couldn't you see she is deranged?!
你看不出她脑子有毛病吗？
Doctor, I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
医生,抱歉让你久等了
Gentlemen, this is now a police matter.
先生们,现在这是警察的事了
You will please stay here until I return.
你们乖乖呆在这等我回来
Let us out of here!
让我们出去
That's out of the question.
想都不要想
Doctor, sorry. What color did you say?
医生,真抱歉,你说什么颜色来着？
- Black? - Black.
-黑色吗？ -黑色
Gentlemen, please have the goodness to be quiet for the moment!
先生们,现在请他妈的安静点
Couldn't you see I try to serve my customer?
没看到我在招呼客人吗？
Sorry.
对不起
And you, little whore, go to bed at once, you depraved creature.
你,小娼妇,快去睡觉,贱货
I'll deal with you after I serve this gentleman.
我招呼完客人再来收拾你
You should have a cloak lined with ermine.
你该穿件有貂皮衬里的斗篷
Okay, that's $74.50.
到了,74块5
Seventy-four fifty. All right.
74块5,好的
There's 80.
这是80
I promised you 50 bucks over the meter, right?
我答应多给你50的,对吧？
I'll make that a hundred, if you wait for me.
如果你在这等我,我会加到100
Just let the meter run.
可以继续打表
I'll give you the other half plus the meter when I get back.
我回来后给你另一半,车费照付
- Okay? - How long you gonna be?
-行吗？ -你要去多久？
I don't know, maybe an hour or more. But maybe only 10 minutes.
不知道,也许会超过一小时, 但也许只是10分钟
I'll leave my stuff here in the back.
我的东西就留在后座上
Good evening, sir.
晚安,先生
Good evening.
晚安
Can we be of any help?
需要我们效劳吗？
I suppose you'd like the password.
我猜你是想要暗号
If you'd like, sir.
只要您不介意
Fidelio.
菲岱里奥
Thank you, sir. We'll run you up to the house.
谢谢,先生,我们送您进去
Good evening, sir.
晚安,先生
Good evening.
晚安
Password, sir?
暗号,先生？
Fidelio.
菲岱里奥
Thank you, sir.
谢谢,先生
I'm not sure what you think you're doing.
我不知道你以为自己在干什么
But you don't belong here.
但你不该来这
I'm sorry, but I think you've mistaken me for someone else.
不好意思, 但我猜你是把我错当成别人了
Please! Don't be foolish.
行了,别装傻了
You must go now.
你得马上走
Who are you?
你是谁
It doesn't matter who I am.
我是谁无关紧要
You are in great danger.
你现在很危险
You must get away while there's still a chance.
趁现在还有机会赶紧走
Would you be so good as to excuse us for a moment?
不介意我们失陪一下吧？
Have you been enjoying yourself?
玩得还开心吗？
Well, I've had a very interesting look around.
四处看看确实很有意思
Do you want to go somewhere a little more private?
想不想去个更隐密点的地方？
Private?
隐密？
That might be a good idea.
也许是个好主意
Here you are. I've been looking all over for you.
原来你在这,我到处都找遍了
May I borrow him for just a few minutes?
我能借走他一会吗？
I promise to bring him right back.
我保证马上带他回来
I don't think you realize the danger you're in now.
你恐怕还没意识到自己现在有多危险
You can't fool them for much longer.
你不可能瞒过他们太久
You've got to get away before it's too late.
趁现在还不太晚你得赶快走
Why are you telling me this?
你为什么要告诉我？
It doesn't matter.
这无关紧要
Who are you?
你是谁？
You don't want to know. But you must go. Now!
你用不着知道,但你必须走,马上
Will you come with me?
你和我一起走吗？
That's impossible.
那不可能
Why?
为什么？
Because it would cost me my life and possibly yours.
因为那会让我送命,也许你也会
Let me see your face.
让我看看你的脸
Go!
快走
Excuse me, sir.
对不起,先生
Are you the gentleman with the taxi waiting for him?
您就是那位让计程车等着的先生吗？
Yes.
是的
Your driver's at the front door and would urgently like a word with you.
您的司机在门口有急事要跟您说
Please, come forward.
请到这边来
May I have the password, please?
请你说出暗号
Fidelio.
菲岱里奥
That's right, sir. That is the password...
没错,先生,那个暗号是用于...
...for admittance.
...入场的
But may I ask, what is the password for the house?
但我想请问,在屋子里的暗号是什么？
The password for the house?
屋子里的暗号？
I'm sorry, I...
抱歉,我...
I seem to have...
我好像...
...forgotten it.
...忘了
That's unfortunate.
那太遗憾了
Because here, it doesn't matter whether you have forgotten it...
因为现在,不管你是忘了...
...or if you never knew it.
...还是你根本不知道
You will kindly remove your mask.
你都只能摘下你的面具
Now...
现在...
...get undressed.
...脱掉衣服
Get undressed?
脱掉衣服？
Remove your clothes.
脱掉你的衣服
Gentlemen, please...
各位,拜托...
Or would you like us to do it for you?
是不是希望我们来替你脱？
Stop!
住手
Let him go.
让他走
Take me!
抓我吧
I am ready to redeem him.
我愿意代替他赎罪
You are ready to redeem him?
你打算代他赎罪？
Yes.
是的
Are you sure you understand what you're taking upon yourself...
你确信你明白让自己置身于此事...
...in doing this?
...会有何后果吗？
Very well.
很好
You are free.
你自由了
But I warn you...
但我要警告你...
...if you make any further inquiries...
...如果你想继续刺探...
...or if you say a single word to anyone...
...或者对任何人泄漏一个字...
...about what you have seen...
...有关你看到的情形...
...there will be the most dire consequences for you...
...就会有最可怕的结果加诸于你...
...and your family.
...和你的家人
Do you understand?
听懂没有？
What is going to happen to that woman?
那个女人会怎么样？
No one can change her fate now.
现在没人能改变她的命运
When a promise has been made here...
一旦立下誓约...
...there is no turning back.
...就无可挽回
Go!
走吧
It's okay.
没事了
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry I woke you up, but I thought you were having a nightmare.
很抱歉吵醒你,我想你是在做恶梦
Oh, God.
天啊
I just had such a horrible dream.
刚才这梦太可怕了
What time is it?
几点了？
It's a little after 4.
四点多了
Did you just get home?
你刚到家？
It took longer than I thought.
比我预计的拖得要久
You must be exhausted.
你一定很累了
Come on, lie down.
来,躺下
What were you dreaming?
你梦见了什么？
Just these weird things.
一些可怕的事
What was it?
是什么？
It was so weird.
太诡异了
Tell me.
跟我说说
We were in a deserted city...
我们在一个荒漠的城市
...and our clothes were gone.
...衣服都不见了
We were naked...
赤身裸体
...and I was terrified...
...我很害怕
...and I felt ashamed.
...觉得很羞耻
Oh, God...
天啊...
And I was angry because I thought it was your fault.
我很生气,因为我觉得这是你的错
You rushed away to go find clothes for us.
你连忙跑去为我们找衣服
As soon as you were gone, it was completely different.
你一走开,情形就完全不同了
I felt wonderful.
我感觉很惬意
Then I was lying in a beautiful garden...
躺在一座漂亮的花园里...
...stretched out naked in the sunlight...
...赤身裸体在阳光下伸着懒腰...
...and a man walked out of the woods.
...有个男人从树林里走了出来
He was the man from the hotel, the one I told you about.
就是我跟你提过,在酒店看到的那个
The naval officer.
那个海军军官
He stared at me...
他向我走过来...
...and then he just laughed.
...然后冲着我笑
He just laughed at me.
他冲着我笑
But that's not the end...
但不止是这些...
...is it?
...是不是？
Why don't you tell me the rest of it?
跟我说说,后来怎么样？
It's too awful.
那太可怕了
It's only a dream.
只是个梦而已
He was kissing me...
他吻我...
...and then we were making love.
...然后我们做爱
Then there were all these other people around us...
有很多人围着我们...
...hundreds of them, everywhere.
...好几百个,到处都是
Everyone was fucking.
所有人都在做爱
And then I...
而且我还...
I was fucking other men.
和其他男人做爱
So many...
很多...
...I don't know how many I was with.
...我都记不清有多少
And I knew you could see me in the arms of all these men...
我知道你能看到我躺在那些男人怀里...
...just fucking all these men.
...和他们做爱
I wanted to make fun of you...
我想让你难堪...
...to laugh in your face.
...在你面前嘲笑你
And so I laughed as loud as I could.
所以我拼命地放声大笑
That must have been when you woke me up.
就在这时你把我叫醒了
Shit!
见鬼
I'll just have a cup of coffee, please.
请给我一杯咖啡
Anything else?
还要什么吗？
No, thank you.
不,谢谢
Excuse me.
对不起
Do you know when they get in next door at the Sonata Cafe?
你知道隔壁的 "奏鸣曲咖啡"酒吧几点开门吗？
I think there's usually someone in the office around 2 or 3.
通常要两三点的样子办公室才会有人
I don't suppose, by any chance, you know Nick Nightingale?
冒昧问一下,你认识尼克-南丁格尔吗？
He's playing piano over there right now.
他眼下在那弹钢琴
Nick Nightingale?
尼克-南丁格尔？
Sure, he comes in here.
认识,他常来这
Look, maybe you can help me...
也许你能帮我个忙...
...because it's important that I get in touch with him.
...因为我有要紧的事要找他
Do you know where he's staying?
你知道他住在哪吗？
I don't know if he'd want me to give out his address.
没有他的同意,我不能把地址告诉别人
It's okay, I'm a doctor.
没关系,我是个医生
I'm actually an old friend of his.
实际上我是他的老朋友
Well, doctor...
医生...
...he'll be playing there tonight. Can't it wait until then?
...他今晚会来演出, 不能等到那时候再说吗？
To be perfectly honest...
坦白跟你说...
...it's a medical matter.
...和他的身体有关
Some tests. I know he'll want to know about them as soon as possible.
是一些检验报告, 我相信他一定想尽快知道结果
Excuse me.
对不起
Hi! How can I help you?
嗨,需要效劳吗？
Can you please ring Mr.Nightingale's room for me?
麻烦你打电话到 尼克-南丁格尔的房间好吗？
I'm sorry, sir, Mr.Nightingale has already checked out.
很抱歉,先生,南丁格尔先生已经退房了
He checked out?
他退房了？
- Did he leave a forwarding address? - No, I'm afraid not.
-他有没有留下联系地址？ -不,恐怕没有
When did he check out?
他几点退的房？
About 5:00 this morning.
大概早上5:00
5:00?
5:00？
That's an early checkout, isn't it?
有点早不是吗？
It is a little on the early side, yeah.
确实有点早
Did you notice anything...
你有没有注意到什么...
...I don't know...
...怎么说呢...
...unusual about him when he left?
...他走时有没有什么不对劲的地方？
Unusual?
不对劲？
Hey, you're not Five-O, are you?
你不会是警探吧？
No, I'm an old friend of his.
不,我是他的老朋友
Really?
真的？
I'm a doctor.
我是个医生
- Well, Bill...? - Sure.
-可以叫你比尔吗...？ -当然
It's funny you should ask that question, Bill...
你问的问题很有意思,比尔...
...because there was something a little strange...
...因为尼克-南丁格尔先生离开时...
...about the way Mr.Nightingale left.
...确实有点奇怪
Really? What was that?
是吗？怎么讲？
He came in this morning, about 4:30 a.m...
他早上4:30左右回来时...
...with two men.
...和另两个人一起
Big guys.
大块头
They were very well-dressed and very well-spoken.
他们衣着得体而且谈吐文雅
But they weren't the kind of people you'd fool around with...
但肯定不是那种好惹的角色...
...if you know what I mean.
...你该懂我的意思
Anyways...
总之...
...I noticed Mr.Nightingale had a bruise on his cheek.
...我发现南丁格尔先生脸上有瘀伤
To be perfectly honest, I also thought he looked a little scared.
老实说,我觉得他看上去有点害怕
Scared?
害怕？
He said he wanted to check out.
他说他要退房
And then he went upstairs to his room with one of the men.
然后和其中一个人一起去了楼上的房间
The other guy stayed down in the lobby and settled his bill.
另一个留在前台替他结了帐
When they came back, Mr.Nightingale tried to pass me an envelope.
他们下来时, 南丁格尔先生想塞给我一个信封
But they saw it and took it...
他们看到就拿走了
...and said that any mail or messages for him...
...还说要是有他的信件或留言...
...would be collected by someone properly authorized to do so.
...会专门指定某个人来领取
And then they just took him off in a car.
然后他们带他上了车
Do you have any idea where they went?
知道他们是去哪吗？
No, not a clue.
不,一点都不知道
I certainly appreciate your help.
真是太感谢你了
Anytime, Bill.
不客气,比尔
Sure.
没问题
Come in.
请进
- Tuna salad and black coffee. - Thanks.
-金枪鱼色拉和黑咖啡 -谢谢
Listen, how's my afternoon looking?
下午有多少预约？
I think it's just Mrs.Akerly at 2:30 and Mrs.Kominski at 4.
2:30是伊克利太太, 4:00是科米斯基太太,就这些
Well, something's come up, and I'm not going to be able to see them.
我有点事,恐怕不能替她们看诊
Please ask Dr.Miller if he can fit them in. Otherwise, just apologize...
米勒医生方便的话就请他代一下...
...and make new appointments. - Sure.
不然就只好另约时间
And please call the garage and have them get my car out in half an hour.
另外请通知车库半小时后把我的车开出来
No problem.
没问题
Any calls for me?
有电话找过我吗？
Dr.Sanders and Mrs.Shapiro.
桑德斯医生和夏普沃太太来过电话
- Hey, gang. - Hi, Daddy.
-嘿,两位 -嗨,爸爸
Look, I got all these right.
看,我全做对了
You got all of those right?
你全都做对了？
Every single one of them?
每道题都是吗？
That's good.
好极了
You hungry?
你饿不饿？
Sort of.
有一点
Want to eat at 7?
7:00吃饭行吗？
Seven? Listen, can we make that earlier?
7:00？ 能不能早一点？
I have some appointments at the office.
我在办公室还有个约会
You have to go out again tonight?
今晚你又得出去？
I'm afraid so.
恐怕是的
Daddy, am I gonna get a puppy for Christmas?
爸爸,我可以要只小狗作圣诞礼物吗？
We'll see about that, okay?
我会考虑的,好吗？
He could be a watchdog...
它可以做看门狗...
We'll see.
再说吧
Come on, baby, let's finish this off.
来吧,宝贝,我们来把这些做完
All right, we have Joe. And Joe has $2.50.
是这样,现在乔有2.5美元
And Mike has $ 1.75.
迈克有1.75美元
Joe has how much more money than Mike?
乔比迈克多多少钱？
$0.75?
0.75美元？
So is it gonna be a subtraction or an addition?
那么这该用减法还是用加法呢？
"How much more" means that it would be a subtraction.
"多多少"就表示应该用减法
Yeah, because you're going to be taking. Right.
对,因为你要算的是差额
And there were all these other people around us.
有很多人围着我们
Hundreds of them, everywhere.
好几百个,到处都是
Everyone was fucking.
所有人都在做爱
And then I... I was fucking other men.
而且我还... 和其他男人做爱
So many...
很多...
...I don't know how many I was with.
...我都记不清有多少
Keep the change. Merry Christmas.
不用找了,圣诞快乐
What is it?
是谁？
Domino?
多米娜？
No, she's not in.
她不在
Are you expecting her back soon?
她会不会很快回来？
No, I'm not.
不会
I have something for her. Can I leave this with you?
我有东西送给她,能麻烦你收一下吗？
Just a minute.
等等
Can I say who it's from?
我该说是谁送的？
Well, just tell her it's from...
就告诉她是...
...Bill.
...比尔
You're Bill?
你就是比尔？
The Bill? You're the doctor who was here last night?
就是那个比尔？昨晚来过的那个医生？
Well, I suppose I am.
我想是的
Domino said how nice you were to her.
多米娜说你对她很好
Did she?
是吗？
Why don't you come in for a second?
愿意进来坐坐吗？
Sure.
当然
I'm Sally.
我叫莎莉
Hello, Sally.
你好,莎莉
So do you have any idea when you expect Domino back?
你估计多米娜什么时候能回来？
I have no idea.
不知道
You have no idea?
不知道？
To be perfectly honest, she may not even be coming back.
老实说,也许她根本不会回来
She may not even be coming back?
也许根本不会回来？
I...
我...
You...?
你...？
I think there's something that I should tell you.
我想...有件事我该告诉你
Really?
是吗？
But I just don't know. I don't know.
但我不知该怎么说
You don't know? Well, what is it?
是吗？什么事？
I don't know whether to tell you this.
不知道该怎么跟你说
Why don't you have a seat?
为什么你不坐下来呢？
Let's sit down.
先坐下吧
- I don't quite know how to say this. - You don't quite know how?
-我不知道该怎么说 -你不知道该怎么说？
Well, considering that you were with Domino last night...
既然你昨晚和多米娜在一起...
...I think it would be only fair to you to let you know...
...我觉得就应该让你知道这件事...
...that she got the results of a blood test this morning...
...今早她拿到了血液检验结果...
...and it was HIV-positive.
...HIV(爱滋病)呈阳性
HIV-positive?
HIV阳性？
I am very, very sorry to hear that.
我非常,非常遗憾听到这事
I mean, it's absolutely devastating.
这是个很大的打击
Listen, can I offer you anything?
想喝点什么吗？
A cup of coffee maybe?
咖啡行吗？
No, thank you.
不用了,谢谢
I think...
我想...
...maybe I'd better be going.
...也许我还是走比较好
- Taxi! - Off duty.
-计程车 -收工了
I'll just have a cappuccino, please.
请给我一杯卡布其诺
I'll bring it over to you.
我会给你送过来
Thank you.
谢谢
- Good evening.
-晚上好
I'm Dr.Harford.
我是哈佛医生
One of my patients was admitted this morning. Miss Amanda Curran.
我有位病人阿曼达-科琳小姐 今早住进了这家医院
Could you please give me her room number?
能告诉我她在几号房吗？
Certainly, doctor. Her name again?
当然,医生,她叫什么？
Curran. Amanda Curran.
科琳,阿曼达-科琳
C-U-R-R-A-N?
C-U-R-R-A-N？
Miss Amanda Curran?
阿曼达-科琳小姐吗？
That's right.
是的
I'm sorry, doctor. Miss Curran died this afternoon.
很遗憾,医生,科琳小姐下午去世了
She died this afternoon?
她死了？
Yes, at 3:45 p.m.
是的,下午3:45
I'm sorry.
很遗憾
Because it could cost me my life...
因为那会让我送命...
...and possibly yours.
...也许你也会
Yes, this is Dr.Harford.
是,我是哈佛医生
Tonight?
今晚？
No, no, that's okay.
不,不,没关系
Please tell him I'll be there in about 20 minutes.
请告诉他我大约20分钟后到
Come in.
请进
Bill, I appreciate you coming. Sorry to drag you out here.
比尔,真感谢你能来, 麻烦你真不好意思
- Let me have your coat. - I was out anyway. Thank you.
-把外套给我吧 -我反正也没事,谢谢
How about a drink?
想喝一杯吗？
- Are you having one? - Sure.
-你来一杯吗？ -当然
What would you like?
想喝什么？
Just a little scotch.
来点威士忌好了
Good.
好的
How do you take it? Neat?
要加什么吗？不加？
Please.
谢谢
That was a terrific party the other night.
那晚的聚会太棒了
- Alice and I had a wonderful time. - Well, good.
-爱丽丝和我都很开心 -那就好
It was great seeing you both.
很高兴你们都能来
Cheers.
敬你
Were you playing?
你正在玩吗？
No, I was just knocking a few balls around.
不,只是随便玩玩而已
- Beautiful scotch. - That's a 25-year-old.
-这酒真不错 -是25年陈的
- I'll send you over a case. - No, please.
-你拿一箱去吧 -不,谢谢
Why not?
干嘛不？
You feel like playing?
想玩玩吗？
No, thanks. You go ahead, I'll watch.
不,谢谢,你继续吧,我看你玩
I was just...
我...
Listen...
听我说...
The reason I asked you to come over is...
我之所以叫你过来...
...I need to talk to you about something.
...是想和你谈件事
Sure.
尽管说
It's a little bit awkward.
有点不太好说
And I have to be completely frank.
但我必须坦白告诉你
What kind of problem are you having?
是不是你有什么问题？
It isn't a medical problem.
不是健康方面的事
Actually...
实际上...
...it concerns you.
...和你有关
I know what happened last night.
我知道昨晚发生了什么事
And I know what's been going on since then.
也知道事情后来是什么样
And I think you just might...
我觉得你也许...
...have the wrong idea about one or two things.
...有一两件事弄错了
I'm sorry, Victor, I...
抱歉,维克多,我...
What in the hell are you talking about?
你到底在说什么？
Please, Bill, no games.
得了,比尔,别装了
I was there.
我当时在场
At the house.
在屋子里
I saw everything that went on.
我看到了发生的一切
What the hell did you think you were doing?
你以为你当时到底在干什么？
I couldn't even begin to imagine...
我根本无从想象...
...how you'd heard about it...
...你是怎么打听到的...
...let alone got yourself through the door.
...更别说你是怎么混进去的
Then I remembered seeing you with that prick piano player...
后来我记起你认识那天晚会上 的那个混蛋钢琴师...
...Nick whatever the fuck his name was, at my party.
...叫他妈尼克什么的那个
And it didn't take much to figure out the rest.
剩下的就很容易解释了
It wasn't Nick's fault.
那不能怪尼克
It was mine.
得怪我
Of course it was Nick's fault.
当然是尼克的错
If he hadn't mentioned it to you, none of this would've happened.
如果他不跟你说就什么事都没有
I recommended that cocksucker to those people...
是我向那些人介绍的这个混蛋...
...and he's made me look like a complete asshole.
...结果他害得我灰头土脸的
What can I say?
我能怎么说呢？
I had...
我...
...absolutely...
...根本...
...no idea you were involved in any way.
...不知道这件事会牵涉到你
I know you didn't, Bill.
这我知道,比尔
But I also know that you...
但我也知道你...
You went to Nick's hotel this morning...
你今早去过尼克住的酒店...
...and talked to the desk clerk.
...和前台服务员聊过
How do you know that?
你怎么知道？
Because I had you followed.
因为我有人跟踪你
You had me followed?
你有人跟踪我？
Okay, okay, I'm sorry.
行了,行了,我很抱歉
All right? I owe you an apology.
行吗？我向你道歉
This was for your own good, believe me.
但这是为你好,相信我
I know what the desk clerk told you. But what he didn't tell you is...
我知道前台雇员跟你说了什么, 但他没告诉你的是...
...all they did was put Nick on a plane to Seattle.
...他们只是把尼克送上了回西雅图的飞机
By now he's probably back with his family...
现在他也许已经到家...
...banging Mrs.Nick.
...正和老婆大干呢
The clerk said he had a bruise on his face.
那个雇员说他脸上有瘀伤
Okay, he had a bruise on his face.
好吧,他脸上是有瘀伤
That's a hell of a lot less than he deserves.
那已经比他该受的惩罚轻多了
I don't think you realize what kind of trouble you were in last night.
我相信你还不知道 自己昨晚遇上的是什么麻烦
Who do you think those people were?
你以为那些是什么人？
Those were not just ordinary people there.
那些人都大有来头
If I told you their names... I'm not gonna tell you their names...
如果我说出他们的名字... 我不会说...
...but if I did, I don't think you'd sleep so well.
...但如果我说出来, 恐怕你会吓得睡不着觉
Was it the second password?
是不是第二个暗号？
Is that what gave me away?
让我露了马脚？
Yes, finally.
可以这么说
But not because you didn't know it.
但不是因为你不知道
It's because there was no second password.
而是因为没有第二个暗号
Of course it didn't help a whole lot that those people arrive in limos...
其他都是次要的, 比如别人都是坐豪华轿车...
...and you showed up in a taxi.
...而你却是坐计程车
Or that they found the receipt from the rental house in your coat...
或是他们在你的 外套口袋里发现一张租服装的收据...
...made out to you-know-who.
...泄漏了你的身份
There was a woman there...
当时在那有个女人...
...who tried to warn me.
...她试着警告过我
I know.
我知道
Do you know who she was?
知道她的身份吗？
She was a hooker.
她是个妓女
Sorry, but...
抱歉,但...
...that's what she was.
...她确实是妓女
A hooker.
妓女
Suppose I told you...
我可以告诉你...
...that everything that happened to you there...
...你在那遇到的每件事情...
...the threats, the girl's warnings...
...那些威胁,那个女孩对你的警告...
...her last-minute intervention...
...她在最后时刻置身其中...
...suppose I said that all of that...
...我得说这一切...
...was staged.
...都是在演戏
That it was a kind of charade.
那只是一种假象
That it was fake.
是假的
Fake?
假的？
Yes. Fake.
对,假的
Why would they do that?
为什么要这样做？
Why?
为什么？
In plain words...
简而言之...
...to scare the living shit out of you.
...就是想把你吓个半死
To keep you quiet about where you'd been...
让你对自己看到的一切...
...and what you'd seen.
...守口如瓶
Have you seen this?
你看过这个没有？
Yes, I have.
是的,我看过
I saw her body in the morgue.
我在停尸房看到了她的尸体
Was she the woman at the party?
她是不是晚会上的那个女人？
She was.
是她
The woman lying dead in the morgue...
躺在停尸房里的那个女人...
...was the woman at the party.
...就是晚会上的那个
Well, Victor, maybe I'm missing something here.
维克多,也许我还漏掉了什么
You called it a fake, a charade.
你说那是假的,是个假象
Do you mind telling me what kind of fucking charade...
那介不介意告诉我哪种该死的假象...
...ends with somebody turning up dead?
...要以有人丧命而告终？
Okay, Bill, let's cut the bullshit. All right?
好了,比尔,我们别说这些废话了,行吗？
You've been way out of your depth for the last 24 hours.
过去24小时你都是在多管闲事
You want to know what kind of charade? I'll tell you exactly what kind.
你想知道是哪种假象？ 那我就告诉你是哪种
That whole play-acted, "take me" phony sacrifice...
那整场演出,那场甘愿以身相代...
...that you've been jerking off with had nothing to do with her real death.
...令你浮想联翩的好戏 和她真正的死因没有半点关系
Nothing happened after you left that hadn't happened to her before.
你走了之后她什么事都没有发生
She got her brains fucked out. Period.
只不过吸毒吸得神智不清了而已
When they took her home, she was just fine...
他们送她回家时她还好好的...
...and the rest is in the paper.
...其他的报纸上都有
She was a junkie. She OD'd. There was nothing suspicious.
她是个毒鬼,吸毒过了量, 根本没什么可怀疑的
Her door was locked from the inside. The police are happy. End of story.
她的门是从里面反锁的, 警察很高兴事情能到此为止
Come on. It was always gonna be just a matter of time with her.
拜托,这种结果对她来说只是迟早的事
Remember, you told her so yourself.
你自己不也说过吗？
You remember, the one with the great tits who OD'd in my bathroom?
记得在我洗手间里有对大奶子的那个吗？
Listen, Bill, nobody killed anybody.
听着,比尔,没有谁杀死任何人
Someone died. It happens all the time.
有人死了,这再普通不过
But life goes on.
但生活还得继续
It always does...
一切照旧...
...until it doesn't.
...到死为止
But you know that, don't you?
你也知道是吧？
I'll tell you everything.
我会原原本本告诉你
Helena's gonna be up soon.
海莲娜就快醒了
She's expecting us to take her Christmas shopping today.
她还盼着我们今天带她去买圣诞礼物
That's nice.
真好看
I could put Sabrina in here.
我能把洋娃娃放在里边
It's really pretty.
它真漂亮
It's old-fashioned.
是老式的
He's big.
它可真大
I hope Santa Claus gets me one of these for Christmas.
我希望圣诞老人能送一个给我作礼物
You do?
是吗？
Well, you're gonna have to wait and see.
那你得等着看会不会
What do you think we should do?
你觉得我们该怎么做？
What do I think we should do?
我觉得该怎么做？
Look, Mommy!
看,妈妈
What do I think? I don't know.
我的想法？我不知道
I mean, maybe...
我是说,也许...
Maybe I think...
我觉得也许...
...we should be grateful.
...我们应该庆幸
Grateful...
庆幸...
...that we've managed to survive through all of our...
...我们能平平安安撑过所有那些...
...adventures...
...冒险...
...whether they were real...
...不管是真实的...
...or only a dream.
...抑或仅仅是一场梦
Are you sure of that?
你肯定那仅仅是一场梦？
Am I sure?
我肯不肯定？
Only as sure as I am...
...我能肯定的只是...
...that the reality of one night...
...一个晚上的真实性...
...let alone that of a whole lifetime...
...远远说不上一辈子...
...can ever be the whole truth.
...能随时做到完全真实
And no dream is ever...
而一场梦也不会...
...just a dream.
...仅仅是一场梦
The important thing is...
重要的是...
...we're awake now...
...我们醒过来了...
...and hopefully...
...而且希望...
...for a long time to come.
...能一直这样下去
Forever.
永远
Forever?
永远？
Let's not use that word. You know?
我们还是别用这个词好吗？
It frightens me.
这让我害怕
But I do love you...
但我真的爱你...
...and you know...
...而且你知道...
...there is something very important...
...有件事非常重要...
...that we need to do as soon as possible.
...我们应该尽快去做
What's that?
是什么？
Fuck.
做爱